Guide to the Sarah P. Duke Gardens records, 1926-2012 UA.10.08.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Garden Drawings and Designs, 1935-1999, Located on-site in oversize storage
  - Miscellaneous, 1934-1993
    - Iris garden, plot plan, George F. Hackney, 1 sheet, blueprint, 1934-1936 (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Office building and tool house, shop drawing, Indiana Limestone Corporation, 1 sheet, blueprint with colored pencil, 1937 Nov. (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Flood control dam and driveway, elevation drawing, William M. Platt, engineer, 1 sheet, blueprint, 1937 Dec. (Oversize-folder 7)
    - General ground plan, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, Prepared from original drawing in the office of Wm. Platt, with additional data on topography, 1937 Dec. (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Spralawn system, working drawing, Munz Spralawn Co., 1 sheet, blueprint, 1937; revised 1938 (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Bridge detail, side elevation drawing, George F. Hackney and Charles F. Knott, 1 sheet, diazo, 1949 (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Bridge, working drawings, George F. Hackney and Charles F. Knott, 2 sheets, blueprints, 1949 (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Preliminary sketches of Sarah P. Duke Gardens, Engineer W.K. Howard, drawn by George Owens, 1 sheet, diazo, 1959 Nov. (Oversize-folder 7)
    - General development plan, Olmsted Brothers, 1 sheet, diazo, 1960 Feb. (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Service building, west elevation and site plan, drawn by George Owen, 1 sheet, diazo, revised, 1960 March (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Gate design development drawing, 1961 Feb. (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Air condition spray pool, plan view and section drawing, 1 sheet, diazo, 1961 March (Oversize-folder 7)
    - South lawn pool, working drawing after T.L. Hardy, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1962 Aug. (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Seeded areas at entrance, plot plan, W.H. Gardner, Jr. and Associates, 1 sheet, diazo, 1962 Sept. (Oversize-folder 7)
    - South lawn pool, working drawing, engineers: Gardner, Elsevier, and Kline, 1 sheet, diazo, revised, 1962 Nov. (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Modern gates, as built 1961 drawing, drawn by LTD, 1 sheet, diazo, 1971 Dec. (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Proposed sprinkler location, working drawing, 1 sheet, pencil and ink on diazo, revised 1975 April (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Storage building, working drawings, 3 sheets, diazo, 1979 Oct. (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Limestone benches, shop drawing, John J. Morton Co., Inc., 1 sheet, diazo with colored marker, 1985 Nov. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Donation depository, plan and elevation drawing Scheme C, 1 sheet, diazo, 1991 (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Plaque inscription drawing honoring the forty-two regional chairmen of the Capital Campaign for Arts and Sciences and Engineering, 1 sheet, electrostatic copy, 1992 (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Pylon and kiosk directory, detail drawings, SouthWood Corporation, 7 sheets, diazo, 1992 (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Office trailer, floor plan drawing, marked jobsite copy, 1 sheet, diazo, 1993 May (Oversize-folder 8)
    - New parking garage, site plan and plant materials schedule, 1 sheet, electrostatic copy, undated (probably 1990's) (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Bridge, presentations drawings, 2 sheets, colored pencil on mat board, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Sarah P. Duke Gardens bronze plaque, inscription drawing, 1 sheet, diazo, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Memorial entrance showing location of posts, working drawing, 1 sheet, pencil on tracing paper, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Memorial entrance showing location of posts, working drawing, 1 sheet, pencil on tracing paper, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Pergola, shop drawings, Carolina Steel and Iron Corp., 3 sheets, blueprints, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Plan suggesting the Hanes Memorial planting, working drawing, 1 sheet, ink on vellum, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Sprinkler plan, working drawing, 1 sheet, diazo, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Drive and fence layout plan, 1 sheet, diazo with pencil and colored pencil, 1961 April (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Entrance gate, detail drawing received by R.H. Fillmore from Barnes Studios, Laverett, Mass., 4 sheets, diazo, and pencil on paper and tracing paper, 1961 Aug. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Portion of new boundary and proposed service road, site plan by T.L. Hardy, 1 sheet, diazo on vellum, 1962 Feb. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Reflecting pool, as built drawing, 1 sheet, diazo, 1962 March (Oversize-folder 8)
    - South lawn pool, working drawing, T.L. Hardy, 1 sheet, diazo, 1962 Aug. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Modern gates, design drawings, by Barnes, 3 sheets, pencil on vellum and diazo, 1962 (Oversize-folder 8)
    - South lawn, drainage plan, T.L. Hardy with added notes by R.H. Fillmore, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1963 April (Oversize-folder 8)
    - South lawn, drainage plan, T.L. Hardy, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1963 April (Oversize-folder 8)
    - South boundary road experimental gully, planting plan, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, approved by R.H. Fillmore, drawn by Jan D. Beaumon, 1965 Oct. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - South boundary road experimental gully, planting plan, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, approved by R.H. Fillmore, drawn by Jan D. Beaumon, 1965 Oct.; revised January 1966 (Oversize-folder 8)
    - South boundary road experimental gully, planting plan, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, approved by R.H. Fillmore, drawn by Jan D. Beaumon, with extra pencil notations on plant locations, 1965 Oct.; revised January 1966 (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Proposed fence, rough sketch by R.H. Fillmore, 1 sheet, diazo with pencil notations, 1967 June (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Proposed fence, rough sketch by R.H. Fillmore, 1 sheet, diazo with pencil notations, 1967 June (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Modern gates, as constructed drawing, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1971 Dec. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Drainage basin, 1 sheet, pencil on graph vellum, by Ed Steffeck based on W.S. Leong, 1978 March (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Limestone benches, detail drawing of leg front and top slab corners, 1 sheet, diazo, 1987 Jan. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - South lawn irrigation plan, working drawing, by William H. Sparrow, Jr., 1 sheet, diazo, 1987 July (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Site upgrade plan (Duke Facilities Management), 1 sheet, electrostatic on paper, 1989 Feb. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - 36th Parallel Monument, design development drawing by Larry T. Daniel, 1 sheet, pencil on graph paper, 1989 May (Oversize-folder 8)
    - 36th Parallel Monument, design development drawing with size notations, by Larry T. Daniel, 1 sheet, pencil on graph paper, 1989 May (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Grading graph (fountains area?), 2 sheets, pencil and colored pencil on graph vellum, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Limestone benches, working drawings, 4 sheets, pencil on vellum, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous grading plan, 1 sheet, pencil on graph vellum, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Pumphouse addition, elevation drawing, 1 sheet, electrostatic copy, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Retention pond cleanout, working drawings, 3 sheets, diazo, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Rose garden with pool in center, working drawing, 1 sheet, diazo, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Spray pond area, simplified plot plan, W.H. Gardner Assoc., 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Sprinkler system for greenhouse, 1 sheet, diazo, 1960 Oct. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Parking lots, Yearby and Anderson, working drawings, 2 sheets, diazo, 1975 (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Atlas St. extension and parking lots I, II, VI, VII, working drawing, 1 sheet, diazo, 1961 June (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Baker parking lot, A street widening and parking lot, working drawing, 1 sheet, diazo, 1961 June (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Terrace Shop, working drawings, 5 sheets, blueprints, 1996 (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Garden Water Course: Topographical plan with plants numbered, 1 sheet, diazo with pencil, 1961 Dec. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Garden Water Course: Topographical plan, 1 sheet, diazo with pencil notations, 1961 Dec. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Garden Water Course: Storm drainage plan, Moriece and Gary, 1 sheet, diazo, 1961 Oct.; revised 1961 Dec. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Garden Water Course: Grading and drainage plan, Moriece and Gary, 1 sheet, diazo, 1962 March (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Garden Water Course: Site Layout and details, Moriece and Gary, 1 sheet, diazo, with 2 overlays, pencil on graph vellum, 1962 March (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Garden Water Course: Sketch by R.H. Fillmore, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1966 Dec. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Garden Water Course: Revised plan, 1 sheet, pencil on tissue paper, 1962 Dec. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Garden Water Course: Topographical map of water course, 1 sheet, diazo, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Service Building(s): Working drawings, 4 sheets, blueprints, 1959-1960 (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Service Building(s): Working drawings, W.K. Howard, engineer, drawn by George Owen, 4 sheets, diazo, 1960 Jan. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Service Building(s): Design proposal, Carr Harrison Pruden and DePasquale, architects, 2 sheets, diazo, 1965 Aug. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Service Building(s): Working drawings, Carr Harrison Pruden and DePasquale, architects, 7 sheets, blueprints, 1966 Sept. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Service Building(s): Topographical survey map of area, 1 sheet, diazo, 1965 Sept. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Service Building(s): Proposed plan, R.H. Fillmore, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1966 Sept. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - Service Building(s): Working drawing of machinery shed, R.H. Fillmore, Larry T. Daniel in consultation with James A. Ward, 1 sheet, pencil on graph vellum, 1974 Jan. (Oversize-folder 8)
  - Ed Steffek Drawings and Designs, 1977, 1981
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Master plan, from William S. Leong master plan 1976, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1977 April (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Pond and shelter, master plan, 1 sheet, pencil on graph vellum, 1981 Oct. (Oversize-folder 8)
  - David L. Longland Drawings, 1972-1977, undated
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Site plan, 1 sheet, diazo, 1975 March (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Garden bridge area, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1975 Sept. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Master plan, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1975 Dec. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Tree plan, 2 sheets, pencil on vellum, 1976 Jan. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Site plan, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1976 Feb. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Spring planting plan, 1 sheet, diazo with pencil notations, 1975 March; updated 1976 June (Oversize-folder 8, Tube 27)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Master plan (revised), 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1976 Oct. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Planting plan (as planted), 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1976 Oct. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Planting plan (as planted), 1 sheet, diazo with pencil additions, 1976 Oct. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Planting plan, 1 sheet, pencil and colored pencil on graph vellum, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Map of H.L.Blomquist Garden, drawn by Marcus H. Olsen with tree and herbaceous plantings marked, 1 sheet, pencil on graph vellum, 1974 June (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Bridge, elevation and detail drawing, by Larry T. Daniel, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1972 Feb. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Bridge, proposed site plan, by Larry T. Daniel, 1 sheet, diazo, 1972 May (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Vine arbor, site plan, after David L. Longland, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1976 Jan. (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Vine arbor, schematic drawing, 1 sheet, diazo, 1977 March (Oversize-folder 8)
    - H.L. Blomquist Garden: Miscellaneous planting plans, 3 sheets, pencil on vellum, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
  - Memorial Garden: UVA Concept Designs, undated
    - Concept drawings, 9 sheets, diazo, undated (Oversize-folder 8)
  - Terrace Planting Plans 1957-1981
    All diazo, pencil and 1 sheet unless noted.
    - Bed numbering/lettering scheme,1957 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Section A, 1957 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Section A, 1957 Spring (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Section B, 1957 Spring (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1957-Spring 1958, pencil on tracing paper, 1957-1958 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring for Summer 1958, 1958 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1958, 1958 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1959, 1958 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1960, 1959 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1960, 1959 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1960, 1959 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1960, 1959 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1961, 1960 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1961, 1961 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1961, 1961 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1961, 1961 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1961, 1961 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1961, 1961 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1961, 1961 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1962, 1961 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1962, 1961 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1962, 1962 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer and Fall 1962, 1962 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1962, 1962 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1963, 1962 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1963, 1962 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer and Fall 1963, 1962 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1963, 1962 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Peony planting plan, marked From Cherry Hill Nurseries, West Newbury, Mass. B.E.K. and R.A.F., 1962 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Reference Map, 1958; 1962 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Planting plan, bed M-4, 1 sheet, pencil on paper, 1963 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Planting plan, bed L-4, 1 sheet, pencil on paper, 1963 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Ideas for 1963-1964, 1963 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1963, 1963 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1964, 1963 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1964, 1964 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1964, 1964 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1964, 1964 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1965, 1964 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Ideas for 1965-1967, 1965 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1965, 1965 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1965, 1965 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1965, 1965 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1966, 1965 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1966, 1966 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1966, 1966 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1966, 1966 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1967, 1966 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Ideas for 1967-1968, 1967 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1967, 1967 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1967, 1967 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1967, 1967 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1968, 1967 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1968, 1968 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1968, 1968 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1968, 1968 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1969, 1968 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1969, 1969 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1969, 1969 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1969, 1969 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1970, 1970 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1970, 1970 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1970, 1970 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1971, 1970 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1971, 2 sheets, 1971 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1971, 1971 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Ideas for 1972, 1972 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1972, 1972 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1974, 1974 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Planting plan, Spring 1975, 1 sheet, diazo with pencil notations, 1975 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1969, 1969 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1970, 1969 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1970, 1970 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1970, 1970 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1970, 1970 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1971, 1970 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1971, 1971 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1971, 1971 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1971, 1971 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1972, 1971 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1972, 1972 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1972, 1972 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1973, 1972 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1973, 1973 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1973, 1973 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1973, 1973 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1974, 1974 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1974, 1974 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1974, 1974 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1975, 1975 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1975, 1975 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1976, 1976 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1976, 1976 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1976, 1976 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1977, 1977 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1977, 1977 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1978, 1977 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1979, 1979 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Spring 1980, 1979 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1980, 1980 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Summer 1981, 1981 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Fall 1980, 1979 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Daylily planting plan, by BEK, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1963 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Peony planting plan, taken from Cherry Hill plan, 1 sheet, pencil on vellum, 1963 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Peony planting plan, section M2 and N2, 1 sheet, diazo with pencil notations, circa 1975 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Peony planting plan, section M3 and N3, 1 sheet, diazo with pencil notations, circa 1975 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Peony planting plan, section M1 and N1, 1 sheet, diazo with pencil notations, circa 1975 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Peony planting plan, section M4 and N4, 1 sheet, diazo with pencil notations, circa 1975 (Oversize-folder 9)
  - Oversize from Fillmore and Daniels papers 1957-1981 (Box 12)
    - Design drawing for Terrace-Pavilion, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Barnes-Brown Studio Memorial Gate Plaque Design (2), Undated (Box 12)
    - Memorial Gate Blueprint (1), 1962 (Box 12)
    - Memorial Gate Sketch (1), Undated (Box 12)
    - Memorial Gate Blueprints (2), 1962 February 14 (Box 12)
    - Storm Drain Plans (4), 1975 (Box 12)
    - Duke Gardens Map (1), Undated (Box 12)
    - Blomquist Gardens Shelter Sketches and Blueprints (10), 1998 (Box 12)
    - Duke Gardens Map (1), Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Memorial Gate Sketches (2), Undated (Box 12)
    - Blomquist Plaque Design (1), 1986, December 3 (Box 12)
    - Greenhouse New Location Blueprint (1), 1977-1978 (Box 12)
    - Azalea Court (1), 1962 May (Box 12)
    - Memorial Gate Plaques (2), 2001 (Box 12)
    - Englewood Cut Stone (3), 1997 September 11 (Box 12)
    - Walks and Ramps Modifications (2), 1981 (Box 12)
    - Terrace Garden Walkway Map (1), 1989 (Box 12)
    - Anderson Gate Plans (2), 1961 December (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Leong Spray Pond (1), Undated (Box 12)
    - Anderson Gate Enterance (2), 1961 October (Box 12)
    - Anderson Gates and Post Design (1), Undated (Box 12)
    - Anderson Gate Lettering Proofs (2), Undated (Box 12)
    - Ramps and Steps (2), 1962 (Box 12)
    - Post Design Main Gate (1), Undated (Box 12)
    - Sketch of Memorial Gate (1), 1936 (Box 12)
    - Blueprint Memorial Gate (1), 1936 (Box 12)
- Plantings Card Catalog, 1934-1995, 13 boxes
  - Bulb-Iris (Box 13)
  - Iris-Narcissus (Box 14)
  - Oriental Poppy-Rockery (Box 15)
  - Trees and Shrubs-Vines (Box 16)
  - Active File: Trees, Shrubs, Vines, A-O (Box 17)
  - Active File: Trees, Shrubs Vines, P-Z; Inactive File: Trees, Shrubs, Vines, A-I (Box 18)
  - Inactive File: Trees, Shrubs, Vines, J-V; Inactive File, Annuals, Bulbs, Ferns, Perennials, P-R (Box 19)
  - Inactive File: Annuals, Bulbs, Ferns, Perennials, S-Z; Inactive File, A-G (Box 20)
  - Inactive File: H-P (Box 21)
  - Chrysanthenum-Cytisus (Box 22)
  - Active File: Annuals, Bulbs, Ferns, Perennials, A-H (Box 23)
  - Active File: Annuals, Bulbs, Ferns, Perennials, H-Z (Box 24)
  - T-Z (Box 25)